<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About Me on Website - Felix Richter</title>
    <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About Me on Website - Felix Richter</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.felixrichter.tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming the Raspberry Pi with Rust 🦀</title>
      <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/rustforraspberrypi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/rustforraspberrypi/</guid>
      <description>This post serves as a summary for how to setup a rust project for the raspberry pi. No previous knowledge about rust is assumed. I also will talk about this topic in public at our local hacker space in the contex of our weekly presentation. The video to the presentation can be found here.
To create a Rust Program for the Raspberry Pi the following steps are required:
Setup Rust Project with cargo Install Rust Arm + Raspberry Pi Toolchain Configure Rust Project for cross compilation Import crate for GPIO Access Profit 💰 Setting up a Rust Project Rust Arm Toolchain Raspberry Pi Environment Configure cross compilation GPIO Access </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Boundary Scan for PCB debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/jtaghardwaredebugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/jtaghardwaredebugging/</guid>
      <description>I did a seminar talk on JTAG and how to use it to check a PCB for errors. For this i designed a little board in order to simulate manufacturing errors. In this post I want to give you a short introduction to JTAG and how to use it.
What is Boundary-scan Boundary-scan was developed to simplify testing of integrated circuits. To do this the Joint Test Action Group introduced the Boundary Scan architecture as a standard and today it has replaced the old testing methods because of its cost efficiency and speed up of test development and execution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Hardware Peripherals</title>
      <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/hardwareperipherals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/hardwareperipherals/</guid>
      <description>Lately I have been doing programming for embedded systems such as the esp32 and esp8266, and additionally I did a course on embedded systems for my masters degree. This introduced me to the wonderful world of programming close to the hardware level, and inspired me to write this post about hardware peripherals.
What are Hardware Peripherals? Hardware Peripherals are specialized pieces of silicon that are built into a processor. They are used to perform a diverse set of task.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
