<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Website - Felix Richter</title>
    <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Website - Felix Richter</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Rust on RISCV (ch32)</title>
      <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/rustriscvdebugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/rustriscvdebugging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this Blog post I will explore the process of setting up a minimal rust project for embedded baremetal development. The focus is on getting up and running including setting up a debugging flow for instruction stepping fully integrated into my editor of choice (emacs).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of 2025 many popular microcontrollers such as the esp32 already have a big rust community and some easy templates to get up and running with rust. But even less popular devices already have basic infrastructure in place, though setting up a project to do development on them is a bit more of an exploratory experience. Still a lot of the heavy lifting has already been solved. I still remember when first started doing some embedded rust development in 2019, there was little to build upon, so getting started involved bootstrapping a peripheral access crate and start writing a hardware abstraction layer. That is to say that within the last six years the ecosystem for embedded rust projects has evolved impressively.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving Desk Device Utilization with Networking</title>
      <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/improvingyourdeskwithnetworking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/improvingyourdeskwithnetworking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past month I have renovated my appartment. Because of this I had to redo my entire desk setup. If you know me that means spending a lot time managing cables 😅.&#xA;But I am really happy with the result. See for yourself …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.felixrichter.tech/desksetup/desk.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1000&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to be flexible in how I use the devices on my desk. I want to switch between using my laptop and desktop without having to replug everything.&#xA;But I also want to be able to use certain devices from both at the same time. I have been using USB Hubs and the like. But I always was left wanting.&#xA;To be fair my current solution is still not as perfect as in my dreams, but it is damn close.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programming the Raspberry Pi with Rust 🦀</title>
      <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/rustforraspberrypi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/rustforraspberrypi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post serves as a summary for a live code I did at our local hacker space. For the full experience please refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/iCbES_JHKyM&#34;&gt;recording&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;Though I probably should warn that the live coding was done in German (and next time I should make sure to increase the font size everywhere for the recording 🙈).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From zero to a working rust project for the raspberry pi. These are the required steps:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Boundary Scan for PCB debugging</title>
      <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/jtaghardwaredebugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/jtaghardwaredebugging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did a seminar talk on JTAG and how to use it to check a PCB for errors. For&#xA;this i designed a little board in order to simulate manufacturing errors. In this&#xA;post I want to give you a short introduction to JTAG and how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-boundary-scan&#34;&gt;What is Boundary-scan&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Boundary-scan was developed to simplify testing of integrated circuits. To do this&#xA;the Joint Test Action Group introduced the Boundary Scan architecture as a standard&#xA;and today it has replaced the old testing methods because of its cost efficiency and speed&#xA;up of test development and execution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Hardware Peripherals</title>
      <link>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/hardwareperipherals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.felixrichter.tech/posts/hardwareperipherals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been doing programming for embedded systems such as the&#xA;esp32 and esp8266, and additionally I did a course on embedded systems for&#xA;my masters degree. This introduced me to the wonderful world of programming&#xA;close to the hardware level, and inspired me to write this post about&#xA;hardware peripherals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-hardware-peripherals&#34;&gt;What are Hardware Peripherals?&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hardware Peripherals are specialized pieces of silicon that are built into&#xA;a processor. They are used to perform a diverse set of task. This includes&#xA;controlling the processors clock speed, power management and communication&#xA;with other devices. They are responsible for configuring the device operation&#xA;and during operation are used to perform tasks in parallel with the main&#xA;cores.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
